umr.com 2008-12-18

# UMR - Privacy Statement

| |   
---|---|---  
| |  | |    
---|---|---|---  
|  | 

|  |   
---|---  
Privacy Statement

**Our Commitment** UMR is committed to protecting the privacy of our customers and their members. Since we collect certain types of information when you visit our Web site and at the time when our online services are used, we believe that it is important to let you know what information is collected, and how the collected information is used and protected. 

**Welcome to UMR**

In visiting our Web site, we want you to know that you have control over your business and personal information. You can visit us on the web without telling us who you are or revealing any business and personal information whatsoever, including your email address. In this case we capture the URL you came from when you arrive at our site as well as which URL you go to next, whether or not this URL is on our site, but no further information. 

**UMR Online Services**

We encourage you to take advantage of our online services. When you use our online services, we can assure you that the personal information you provide us is managed with care. 

In order to use these services, we will ask for information about you such as name, business and e-mail address. Within each of these services areas on our Web site, you will be informed of the manner information will be collected and used. We know how important your privacy is to you and we appreciate you trusting us to handle your business and personal information responsibly and with integrity. 

**Your Personal Information**

You do not have to give us personal information to visit our Web site until you wish to enter a restricted area. By personal information we mean data that is unique to an individual such as a name, address, social security number or telephone number. We request personal information from you at our site in order to deliver requested materials to you and deliver a service. We do not sell, trade or rent your personal information to others under any circumstances. 

We collect only personal information which you choose to provide to us. By using our Web site you agree to the uses of your personal information described in this notice. If at any time this policy changes, those changes will be posted to this page so that you are aware of our intent to better protect your privacy. 

**Confidentiality Practices**

At UMR, we support the concept of total confidentiality. We also hold our business associates and our affiliates to similar confidentiality standards. All personal information or other confidential information must be used and disclosed in a manner consistent with applicable federal and state statutes and regulations, contractual obligations, and UMR policies and procedures. Confidential information includes but is not limited to, protected health information, non-public financial information, and trade secrets.   
  
_**Protected health information** _is individually identifiable health information that is transmitted or maintained by our customers and UMR in performance of our service agreement. This includes information in electronic, paper and oral form. If an individual's past, present, or future medical information can be discovered from the information it is protected. Protected health information may be used and disclosed solely for business activities related to health plan payment and health care operations as defined in the HIPAA privacy rule. 

_**Non-public financial information** _ includes confidential information of a financial nature that is shared with UMR in the course of providing products and services to current, prospective or prior customers. This information is not otherwise available to the public and includes but is not limited to the following: credit history, financial benefits, business records, accounting, contracts, claims, policy information, and any other data financial in nature. 

_**Trade secrets** _include any proprietary information of our current, prospective or prior customers that is obtained through the course of business activities, and through the provision of products and services. This information is not otherwise available to the public and includes but is not limited to the following: business records, contracts, claims, products, business methods, data processing procedures, marketing strategies, pending projects or proposals, mailing lists, and any other information related to an organization's activities, products or services. 

**Information Collection and Use**

We collect certain information that users voluntarily submit and certain information related to Internet usage. We do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we know is a child under the age of 13 as we do not allow them to register. 

We do not use information obtained from users to promote material goods, our own or those of business partners. We do use information obtained from Users who complete a Health Risk Assessment or a Precious Cargo Enrollment Form, or use the secure messaging with a nurse feature, or use the condition center diaries, or other means to promote its voluntary health management services, such as the Disease Management Program, and the Precious Cargo Program among others.   

We collect data elements on prescribed forms. In the course of conducting our business we may share information you provide to us strictly on an as needed basis or otherwise required by law. In certain situations, and in no event contrary to applicable public policy, we would share information about you to: 1) our affiliated companies in order to provide a service to you; 2) a third party if reasonably necessary to enable them to perform services for us such as claims inquiries, appraisals, or the detection of fraud or material representations; 3) governmental authorities; 4) persons or organizations conducting legitimate research. 

UMR does not use, disclose, sell or transfer any personal information without consent unless required or permitted by law or regulation. In cases of permitted disclosure, we will disclose information in compliance with applicable laws and regulations and will require the recipient to protect the information and use it only for the purpose provided. The information we collect and maintain may be retained indefinitely.

**Online Tracking**

 __

_  
**Click Streams** __  
_We may capture click streams to help us learn what parts of our site are most popular and among which audiences. We may also use them to help us optimize our user interface, to analyze site usage statistically, to improve content, and to customize our site's content and layout. In short, we use this information to allow us to tailor our site and to meet your needs better. We analyze click stream data to track trends and behaviors--not individuals. We are interested in our audience size, return visit rate, and similar data on an aggregate basis. We also capture date and time information of visits, pages visited, and the time you spend with us.

 _ **Cookies** __  
_Cookies are pieces of information that a site transfers to your computer's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. They can make the site more useful by storing information about your preferences at our site. It is almost standard for any interactive Web site to use cookies. Cookies do not identify a user, but they do identify a user's computer. Most browsers are set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies, however certain areas of the site may not function properly or conveniently for you.

We do not use cookies to track, report on activity when you are not on our site, or pass your data to other sites. We do not use cookies to collect personal information such as your email address. We do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information. We do not knowingly make any of the foregoing information we collect available to anyone else. We make no attempt to look at or examine other cookies or information that may be stored on your computer.

**Use of E-mail**

E-mail messages sent in clear text over the public Internet can be observed by an unintended third party. Nonencrypted Internet email communications may be accessed and viewed by other Internet users without your knowledge and permission while in transit to us. 

If you wish to keep your information private, please do not use email to communicate information to us or request information from us that you consider confidential. If you wish, you may contact us instead via telephone at the phone number provided on your member ID card. You are responsible for supplying us with reliable means to contact you should you agree to certain services.

**Protected Areas of UMR Web Site**

There are some areas of our Web site where we have made special provisions for a more secure environment in which we exchange information with you. It is designed to give our customers and members a protected means of gathering information and transacting benefits administration over the Internet. In order to enter and use these areas of our Web site, you will need to use access codes we provide you for authentication purposes. These access codes are meant for the exclusive use of each individually designated user. Applicable law, contract, and professional ethics to access and use these areas of our Web site bind individual users. 

All of the data we collect is protected against unauthorized access. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online. Secure servers and encryption technology safeguards all personal information.

**Correcting or Removing Your Personal Information**

****If you would like to correct any personal information you have provided to us or request that we limit or remove your information from our records, contact us at 1-866-881-0800. We will delete your personal information where feasible. We will respond to you within 3-5 business days.

If you do not receive adequate resolution of a privacy-related problem, you may mail: 

UMR   
115 W. Wausau Ave.  
Wausau, WI 54401

**Links to Other Sites**

We may provide links to other Web sites not owned or controlled by us that we think might be useful or of interest to you. We cannot however be responsible for the privacy practices used by other Web site owners or the content or accuracy of those other Web sites. Links to other Web sites do not constitute or imply endorsement by us of the Web sites, any products or services described on these sites or any other material contained in them. Contact those Web sites for their individual privacy policies. 

We carefully select linked sites for the purpose of pointing the user to additional information or resources that may be helpful. We review all linked sites based on source, content, workability, graphics and scope. We do not accept links to sponsored health information content that we know either contains false or misleading claims or promotes ineffective or dangerous products.

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to make changes to our privacy policy. We encourage you to review the Web site and these terms periodically for any updates or changes. Your continued access or use of this Web site shall be deemed your acceptance of this privacy policy. 

| 

**_Important Links_**  
  
©2008 UnitedHealthcare Services, Inc.  
No part of this web site may be reproduced without permission.  
|Terms of use|Privacy Statement|
